#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/wkandek (LinkedIn)

www.kandek.com (Personal) www.advisorycloud.com/profile/ Wolfgang-Kandek (Personal)

## Top Skills

Information Security
Technical Architecture
Engineering Leadership

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Native or Bilingual)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

#### **Patents**

Systems and methods for assessing the compliance of a computer across a network

System and Method for performing remote Security Assessments of firewalled Computer

# Wolfgang Kandek

Head of Cloud Operations and Site Reliability Engineering San Jose, California, United States

## Summary

I have 20+ years of experience in developing and managing information systems. My focus has been on Unix-based server architectures and application delivery through the Internet. At Marketo, I was responsible for the availability and performance of the main Marketo SaaS application and the migration of that application from on-prem to public cloud. Prior to Marketo, I was a Director of SRE at Google and the CTO at Qualys. Earlier in my career, I held a variety of technical positions at a number of startups and established companies, EDS, MCI, and IBM. I received my Master's and Bachelor's degrees in Computer Science from the Technical University of Darmstadt, Germany.

In my CTO role, I had frequent speaking engagements at security events and forums including Black Hat, RSA Conference, InfoSecurity UK, and The Open Group. I used to blog at the Laws of Vulnerabilities site - http://laws.qualys.com

Specialties: Internet service design, server architecture, high availability systems, performance, and security architecture and implementation

https://www.advisorycloud.com/profile/Wolfgang-Kandek

# Experience

Marigold SVP Site Reliability Engineering November 2021 - March 2023 (1 year 5 months)

Responsible for the performance and availability of the Cheetah Digital SaaS applications, on-premises and AWS cloud, both .NET, Windows, SQL-Server and Rails, Linux, MySQL. Managed a team of 90+ platform engineers. Increased uptime and lowered incident occurrences. Revamped incident process and tools. Optimized AWS costs using Savings Plans and Reserved

Instances. Implemented instance monitoring using AWS APIs. Migrated onpremises systems to AWS using AWS MAP programs.

Wikimedia Foundation Site Reliability Engineering Manager April 2020 - November 2021 (1 year 8 months)

Responsible for the performance and availability of the Wikipedia application. I managed the core application SRE team directly.

#### Marketo

VP Site Reliability Engineering September 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 4 months) San Mateo, CA

Responsible for the performance and availability of the Marketo SaaS application in the legacy on premise global environment. Improved overall speed by 2x and uptime to 99.99%, reduced incidents. Implemented SSL certificate management system improving service time by 400%. In addition, in charge of its migration to the Google Cloud Platform a multi-month effort of transporting the application to GCP, porting where possible and using Google provided technology wherever of advantage. Implemented SRE teams and synchronized with the company DevOps movement. Evaluated CloudSQL as a replacement for hundreds of MySQL databases, Google Dataproc for on-premise Hadoop, Kubernetes as a virtualization replacement, MongoDB Atlas vs. local MongoDB and Kafka service options vs. local Kafka.

### Google

Director Site Reliability Engineering July 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 3 months) Sunnyvale

Responsible for the Corp Eng Site Reliability Engineering teams in Sunnyvale, New York and Sydney. Corp Eng SRE is in charge of internal Google infrastructure such as DHCP and DNS, plus a large set of internal business applications.

Qualys 14 years

CTO July 2002 - June 2016 (14 years) Redwood City As the CTO for Qualys, I was responsible for the technological innovation of the Qualys platform and its acceptance by the security market. I represented the company at industry conferences and client meetings, formulating general technical tendencies in the security industry and requirements for our customers in general.

VP of Engineering 2007 - 2008 (1 year)

As VP of Engineering developed 3 new product lines (PC, WAS, MDS) for the QualysGuard SaaS (Linux, Apache, Oracle, PHP) platform. Initiated refactoring of the appliance code base (C/C++) and migration to a new internal scripting language (Lua). Grew the engineering team by 50% from 40 to 60 engineers. Implemented the first offsite Qualys engineering center in Beijing, China. As Director and later VP of Operations maintained the Qualys SaaS platform through periods of substantial growth from an initial footprint of tens of servers to hundreds of servers and thousands of appliances. Grew the Operations team from 3 system administrators to 15 system and database administrators. Improved uptime from 99.5% to 99.95%. Implemented performance and availability monitoring. Conducted SAS70 audits on Qualys Operations. Negotiated national and international datacenter deals.

VP of Operations 2005 - 2008 (3 years) Redwood City

Director of Operations July 2002 - 2005 (3 years)

Myplay
Director of Network Operations
June 2001 - July 2002 (1 year 2 months)

iSyndicate
Director of Operations
January 2000 - June 2001 (1 year 6 months)

MCI Systemhouse Technical Architect October 1998 - January 2000 (1 year 4 months)

Hypermedia

Consultant 1993 - October 1998 (5 years)

IBM System Analyst 1990 - 1993 (3 years)

# Education

Technische Universität Darmstadt MS, Computer Science · (1983 - 1989)